# RICARDO OLGUÍN MONTERRUBIO

Address: AV. MÉXICO 1620 INT. 108 COL SAN MARCOS, CDMX, C.P. 16050

Mobile: 5535656005.

Email: ricch96@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL RESUME

I graduated in Oil and Gas Engineering, enthusiastic about work experience in the Hydrocarbons sector. I worked at Gas Uribe company as a management trainee also as a sales manager in food and beverages department at KidZania, and as a primary support at TTEC México and Teleperformance customer service. Currently a student in the Oracle Next Education Program

WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Bilingual Customer Service Representative** · Teleperformance CDMX.

Mexico City, CDMX - October 2021 - December 2022

• International Customer Services, for the company CENTENE Corporation through a digital platform.

## **Bilingual Customer Service Representative · TTEC Mexico.**

Mexico City, CDMX - October 2020 - January 2021.

• International Customer Services, for the company Best Buy through a digital platform.

#### Internship at Gas Uribe · Gas Licuado de México S.A. de C.V.

Mexico City, CDMX - August 2019 - December 2019.

- Perform activities within L.P. Gas Plant to know the process and how the different areas of work are directed, to lead a manager position.
- Trained to lead a L:P. Gas Plant
- Trained to be Manager of an L.P. Gas Plant.

Formation

#### Software Developer · Oracle Next Education, Alura

Mexico City, CDMX - April 2023 - September 2023.

**Oil & Gas Engineering ·** UVM University of Mexico Valley Campus Coyoacán CDMX, Mexico. August 2015 - December 2019

- Specialization in Oil and Gas.
- Degree in process

High School  $\textbf{Certificate} \cdot \textbf{UVM}$  University of Mexico Valley Campus Tlalpan CDMX, Mexico 2015.

Languages

Spanish - Native

**English - Advanced Level Course - (C1) ·** The Anglo, CDMX, Mexico City. (currently) (Certification B2 First)

# RICARDO OLGUÍN MONTERRUBIO

Address: AV. MÉXICO 1620 INT. 108 COL SAN MARCOS, CDMX, C.P. 16050

Mobile: 5535656005.

Email: ricch96@hotmail.com

### Courses or Certifications

**Certificate in Course Rig Pass (2018)** Industrial Safety CAPINSER Industrial Training and Services of Veracruz S.A. of C.V.

- Implementation of FireFighting.
- Implementation of First Aid.
- Implementation of Personal Protection Equipment in Petroleum Platform.

Certificate in Gas Checker. (2017) Petrochemicals  $\cdot$  CAPINSER Industrial Training and Services of Veracruz S.A. of C.V.

- Gas checker vocational training certificate.
- Gas checker in confined spaces.
- Implementation of Autonomous Air Team.

**L.P. Gas Company Directors and Managers Update and Training Seminary Course (2019)** Mexico Gas - City of Mexico

**Programing Course**: Languages HTML, CSS and JavaScript for Web design. (currently)

#### **Other Courses:**

- AutoCAD Basic.
- Intermediate Excel
- Intermediate Word.
- Intermediate Power Point